MIRO ABDALIAN

Software Developer

9563 Tujunga, CA 91042 | (818) 479-1167 | miroabdalian@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Portfolio</u> | <u>GitHub</u>

PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

Bringing 1+ years of experience leading full-stack web projects, including gathering user requirements, producing code, creating mockups, performance testing, and software optimization. Focused on creating clean and robust code with exceptional security. Dedicated to achieving compatibility targets while meeting and exceeding customer demands.

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

Strongest Areas: Data Structures, Algorithms, Object Oriented Programming

Programming Languages: C/C++, Java, Python, Javascript

Libraries/Frameworks: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Redux, Flutter, Git

Web: HTML5, JSON, XML, CSS3, SASS

Database: MongoDB, Firebase, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Language: English (Fluent), Farsi (Native), Armenian (Native)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PROJECTS

Online Store – eCommerce Web Application

React, Redux, Firebase

- Developed a single-page eCommerce web application from scratch
- Implemented Firebase authentication to allow users to sign in with two methods
- Resolved CSS conflicts by updating all SASS files to Styled Components
- Managed states using Context to avoid props drilling

Inventory Management Web Application

React, Node.js, ExpressJS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

- Lead a team of two to develop a custom inventory management web application with React and NodeJS
- Ensured client satisfaction by facilitating client meetings, gathering project specifications, and demonstrating active listening and friendly professionalism
- Distributed tasks between developers for each sprint and ensured everyone was on track

February 2022 – March 2023

July 2022 – February 2023

- Developed and modified 20+ custom components to improve app performance in collaboration with team members
- Developed a REST API with Node and Express to implement CRUD operations
- Used benchmarking tools to measure performance to distinguish slow components
- Enhanced security measures by creating logging APIs to monitor and track unexpected behaviors
- Revenue 10K

Image Recognition Web Application

React, Node.js, Clarifai, PostgreSQL

- Developed a single-page web application using React and Node.is
- Implemented user authentication and authorization using JSON Web Token to improve app security
- Reduced development time by integrating Clarifai image recognition API into the app
- Created a Heroku Postgres database to allow for easy and fast access to user data

WORK EXPERIENCE

Instructional Teaching Assistant

Cal Poly Pomona Foundation Inc.

Assisted students with programming assignments by providing resources/code debugging support

July 2021 - December 2022

June 2021 – July 2022

EDUCATION, AWARDS, AND CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

California State Polytechnic University, Pomona

Academic Projects:

On-Time (Flutter Mobile App) – Developed a personal meeting scheduler mobile app with Flutter and Firebase and published it on Google Play.

Page Popularity (Python Script) – Created a crawler with Scrapy library to measure the most popular page using the original PageRank algorithm.

Montecarlo (Parallel Processing) – Developed three programs to compute Monte Carlo estimates of pi using Threads in C/C++, MPI, and CUDA platforms.

Machine Learning Model – Created machine learning models to detect fraudulent credit card activities using scikit-learn, Panda, and Numpy libraries.

Cal Poly Pomona President's Honor List

California State Polytechnic University, Pomona

July 2020 – December 2022 Pomona, CA

NS

2020 – 2022 Pomona, CA

React, NodeJS, Express & MongoDB - The MERN full-stack Guide

URL:https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-ac94fccc-2471-414bb200-782d7aa3c0b7/

The Complete Web Developer in 2023: Zero to Mastery

URL:https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-36db94fd-039d-47afaac2-e93a99379d32/

SQL for Data Science March 14, 2021

URL: https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/ certificate/9P7FWPK6JZWJ

Object-Oriented Data Structures in C++

URL: https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/ certificate/Y5YFNAXQXMJY

February 6, 2023

December 25, 2022

December 15, 2020